# SatheeshKumar Vajravelu

Senior Manager

Has around 22+ years of experience in the IT industry. Played various roles such as Project Manager, Scrum Master, **Data Scientist** and Technical Leader in Retail Banking Domain. Managed multiple Java based projects end to end. **Well versed in AIML / Python & completed many use cases using various Machine Learning and Deep Learning algorithms.** 



gem.satheesh@gmail.com

+91 9884777994

Plot 18 Door 4/42 Agathiyar street, Sri Sastha Nagar, Santhoshapuram, Chennai-600073, Chennai, India, Chennai, India

la.utexas.edu/texasexeced/digitalVerific ation.html?key=gRSZc

linkedin.com/in/satheeshkumarvajravelu

github.com/satheesh1974/AIML-Projects 🕠

# **WORK EXPERIENCE**

# Senior Manager

Standard Charted Bank

07/2019 - Present

Chennai, India

Responsibilities

- Manage End to End delivery of all the projects under the given Portfolio for AME region for SC Mobile application
- Daily Scrum calls / Project Weekly Calls with all required interface teams and other stakeholders / Status Reporting
- Manage Project Financials / Risk and Communication / Change / Release

## Manager

Capgemini India Pvt Ltd

10/2014 - 06/2019

Chennai, India

Responsibilities

- Manage End to End delivery of all the projects under the given Portfolio
- Manage Project Financials / Risk and Communication / Change / Release

### Consultant

Wipro Technologies Ltd

12/2010 - 10/2014

Chennai, India

Responsibilities

- Manage delivery of all the projects for the assigned client
- Manage Project Financials / Risk and Communication / stakeholders / Status Reporting and People Management

# **Associate Consultant**

Polaris Software Labs Ltd

09/2003 - 11/2010

Chennai India

Responsibilities

 Application Design, Development & Implementation of Integration Layer, Code Review & Test case Review, Mentoring and Training project team

#### **Programmer**

Altosys Software Technologies Ltd

11/2000 - 09/2003

Chennai, India

Responsibilities

Coding and Unit testing, Build and Deployment

# **SKILLS**



#### **CERTIFICATIONS**

Post Graduate Program in Artificial Intelligence and Machine Learning

Certified Blockchain Solution Architect from Blockchain Training Alliance

Certified Blockchain Expert-V2 from Blockchain Council

Corda Certified Developer from R3

Sun Certified Java Programmer for JDK 1.4 Platform

Professional Scrum Master (PSM1) from Scrum.Org

Project Management Professional (PMP) from PMI

#### **EDUCATION**

Bachelor of Engineering (06/1992 - 06/1996) University of Madras

#### INTERESTS

